We will spend the next several topics going
through some pretty typical situations we see
in queries. For the first few situations,
the starting point will be this query,
which lists people and their
addresses. I will execute this as is,
and we have a solid list, but what if we
want to sort the list? The ORDER BY clause
is used to sort information. At the end of
the query, I will type ORDER BY LastName
to sort this on the last name column. I
will execute this statement, and now this is
alphabetical by LastName. We only need one ORDER
BY clause for multiple columns in a sort. I will
add FirstName and then execute this again, and now
this is sorted by LastName and then by FirstName.
To sort a column in descending order, we
just need to add the letters DECS at the end
of whichever column we want in descending
order, which will be the LastName field.
I will execute this again, and now we have the
last names sorted alphabetically from Z to A
and then within each last name,
by first name from A to Z.